The most daring rescue mission of our time is a story that has never been told
The Great Raid is a action, history, war film directed by John Dahl.
As World War II rages, the elite Sixth Ranger Battalion is given a mission of heroic proportions:
push 30 miles behind enemy lines and liberate over 500 American prisoners of war.
Lt. Colonel Mucci, played by Benjamin Bratt.
Captain Prince, played by James Franco.
Margaret Utinsky, played by Connie Nielsen.
Lt. Paul Colvin, played by Logan Marshall-Green.
Major Gibson, played by Joseph Fiennes.
Captain Redding, played by Marton Csokas.
The Great Raid is a 2005 internationally co-produced war film about the Raid at
Cabanatuan on the island of Luzon, Philippines during World War II.
Directed by John Dahl, the film stars Benjamin Bratt, James Franco, Connie Nielsen,
Marton Csokas, Joseph Fiennes with Motoki Kobayashi and Cesar Montano.
It showcases the efforts of American soldiers and the Filipino resistance
guerrilla, rescuing Allied prisoners of war from a Japanese POW camp.
Filming took place from July to November 2002, but its release was
delayed several times from the original target of fall 2003.
It received mixed reviews from critics, and was a commercial failure, having grossed
only $10.8 million against a production budget of $60–80 million.
The film explores themes of based on novel or book, war
crimes, narration, world war ii, prisoner of war.